<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Shawn&#39;s Homepage</title>
        <link>https://shawnmenz.github.io/</link>
        <description>Learn and Note</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>mr.zexuan.meng@gmail.com (Zexuan Meng)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>mr.zexuan.meng@gmail.com (Zexuan Meng)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 16:05:41 -0600</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://shawnmenz.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>A Brief Introduction of LLM</title>
    <link>https://shawnmenz.github.io/posts/llm/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 16:05:41 -0600</pubDate>
    <author>Zexuan Meng</author>
    <guid>https://shawnmenz.github.io/posts/llm/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[What is an LLM? LLM is short for Large Language Model. All the LLMs are language models, but not all language models are LLMs. The distinctions between large and &lsquo;regular&rsquo; are 2 key properties, quantitatively and quanlitatively. Quantitatively means the number of parameters used in the model is pretty large. Qualitatively means that when a language model becomes large, something remarkble will happen.
Zero-shot Learning This terminology means that the model can perform a task even if it has not been explicitly trained to do it.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Docker</title>
    <link>https://shawnmenz.github.io/posts/docker/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 14:19:21 -0600</pubDate>
    <author>Zexuan Meng</author>
    <guid>https://shawnmenz.github.io/posts/docker/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[An Introduction In the past, transitioning a software application from code to production was a painfully slow process. Developers often struggled with the tedious task of managing dependencies while setting up their test and production environments. Docker, a type of container technology, emerged as a solution to alleviate this pain.
From Bare Metal to Docker Bare Metal: The applications ran directly on the physical server (Bare Metal). Teams purchased, racked, stacked, powered on, and configured every new machine.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>A Brief Introduction of UX Design</title>
    <link>https://shawnmenz.github.io/posts/uxdesign/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 22:24:38 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Zexuan Meng</author>
    <guid>https://shawnmenz.github.io/posts/uxdesign/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The basics of user experience design Definitions User experience: How a person, the user, feels about interacting with, or experiencing, a product.
Product: A good, service or feature.
Characteristics of a good user experience Primary characteristics
usable Equitable enjoyable useful User experience career Interaction designer: Interaction designers focus on designing the experience of a product and how it functions. Visual designer: Visual designers focus on how a product or technology looks.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>SQL</title>
    <link>https://shawnmenz.github.io/posts/sql/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 17:46:08 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Zexuan Meng</author>
    <guid>https://shawnmenz.github.io/posts/sql/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Role of SQL SQL as a query language SQL is the standard query language for retrieving data from relational databases SQL is a standard and is supported by virtually all relational databases in the same manner. Queries built for one database generally run without modification against another database. Many vendors provide extensions to SQL for analytics and special data types. Terminology Term Definition Alternate Terms Entity A concept, event, role, place, or physical object that must be tracked,e.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Database</title>
    <link>https://shawnmenz.github.io/posts/database/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 23:17:07 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Zexuan Meng</author>
    <guid>https://shawnmenz.github.io/posts/database/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Two approach to store data File based Approach Problems with the file-based approach Definition of data was embeded into the application programs, rather than being stored separately and independently No control over access and manipulation of data beyond that imposed by application programs Disadvantages to the file-based approach Separation and isolation of data Duplication of data Dependence between the application and the data store Incompatible file formats Programs are written to satisfy one specific data request Database Approach Problems with the database approach All data is pooled together, some data might not be shared with others Database View Allows each user to have his or her own definition of the database A view provides access to a subset of the database View mechanism is imperative if we want to secure the data Benefits Reduce complexity Provides a level of security Provides a mechanism to customize the appearance of the database Present a consistent, unchanging picture of the structure of the database, even when the underlying structure og the database has changed Database A database can be defined as a collection of logically related data from which users can efficiently retrieve the desired information.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>HUGO</title>
    <link>https://shawnmenz.github.io/posts/hugo/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 22:47:27 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Zexuan Meng</author>
    <guid>https://shawnmenz.github.io/posts/hugo/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Create a new website Install Hugo # install on Mac brew install hugo # verify hugo version Create a site hugo new site site_name Add a theme Find a favorate theme and download it from Github
cd site_name git init git submodule add http://github.com/theme.git themes/theme_name Then, remember to update configuration file(config.toml). In this tutorial I choose the LoveIt theme
theme = &#39;theme_name&#39; Add Content Simply using hugo new, we can add content easily.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Basic R</title>
    <link>https://shawnmenz.github.io/posts/basicr/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 10:51:10 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Zexuan Meng</author>
    <guid>https://shawnmenz.github.io/posts/basicr/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Basic R Note The most common use of R is to analyze and visualize data.
In R, Comments starts with #.
Variables A variable is created the moment you first assign a value to it (similar to Python). In order to assign a value to a variable, use &lt;-. &lt;&lt;- is global assigner. Multiple variables can be assigned with multiple &lt;- in one line. var1 &lt;- var2 &lt;- var3 &lt;- &#34;test_text&#34; variable names start with a letter and can be letters, digits, .]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
